Now, let's go back to our press conference.
现在回到我们的记者招待会来
What we want to do is declare an array of strings that holds all our news outlet names.
我们要声明一个字符串数组 在里面存放我们所有新闻媒体的名字
Something that looks like this.
就像这样
To do that, we type in string followed by
要实现这个操作 我们要输入 string
the square brackets which means that we're creating an array of strings.
然后是方括号 说明我们在创建的是字符串数组
And then, the name of our array,
然后是数组名字
in this case, newsOutlet,
也就是 newsOutlet
followed by equals and the curly brackets and inside,
然后是等号和花括号
we list all the values we want to store.
花括号里面列举出我们想存放的所有值
Then, say we want to pick a certain value in the array,
假设我们想从数组中挑出某个值
we just go ahead and say system.out.print and then,
我们可直接输入 System.out.print
newsOutlet of index two.
然后是 newsOutlet [2]
So, we're basically pointing to the string of index two.
由此我们指定了索引为 2 的字符串
Zero, one, two which is going to be CNN,
0、1、2 所以是 CNN
so the output is CNN.
所以输出会是 CNN
And basically, you have chosen someone to ask the first question.
也就是说 你已经选了某人来回答第一个问题了
But in our initial problem,
但我们原本的问题是
we wanted this to be random.
随机选人
We wanted to randomly pick a news outlet.
我们想随机挑出一个新闻媒体
Well, if you remember,
如果你还记得的话
we use Math.random earlier to generate random numbers for us.
之前我们曾用 Math. random 来生成随机数
This might come in handy now.
这个函数现在就派上用场了
Just like we did before,
就像之前一样
we will generate a random number and store it into the double variable, lucky.
我们生成一个随机数 然后将其存放到双精度变量 lucky 中
So, we go double lucky equals Math.random.
所以我们这么输入 double lucky = Math. random ( )
Remember that this generates a random number between zero and one.
记住 这会生成一个在 0 和 1 之间的随机数
So we need to multiply that by 10 to get a fractional number between zero and 10,
所以我们需要将随机数乘以 10 从而获得一个在 0 和 10 之间的分数
which is the number of news outlets that we have.
这也正是到访新闻媒体的数量
Remember that lucky times equals 10 is just
记住 lucky *= 10
multiplying lucky by 10 and updating itself with that new value.
只是将 lucky 乘以 10 并将其更新为该乘积
And then, we want to cast that variable into
之后 我们需要把这个变量转换为整数
an integer so that we don't get a fractional number anymore,
这样我们得到的就不会是分数了
but we get a whole integer number and that's between zero and nine.
而是一个在 0 和 9 之间的整数
The way we do casting is we just write the type that we
转换的办法是 写出要转换的类型
want to cast it to between brackets just before the variable name here.
放到这个变量名前面的括号里
And then we can store that in an integer called luckyIndex.
然后将转换结果赋值给整数 luckyIndex
So now, we end up with this luckyIndex variable that is between zero and nine,
现在我们有了变量 luckyIndex 范围在 0 和 9 之间
and it is an integer so we can access any particular part of the array.
而且该变量是个整数 所以我们可以访问数组的任一部分了
So the last thing we want to do is print out
最后我们要输出
the name of the news outlet who we randomly picked.
随机选出的新闻媒体名称
So we go ahead and say system.out.print,
所以我们这么写 System.out.print
and then we say newsOutlet, square brackets, luckyIndex.
然后是 (newsOutlet [luckyIndex] )
So based on the random number that was generated,
根据随机数生成的值
this luckyIndex can be anything between zero and nine.
这个 luckyIndex 会是 0 和 9 之间的任意值
So we randomly pick one of those and displayed it in the print screen.
所以我们随机选出一个 将其显示在输出屏幕上
Let's trace a few examples and see what's happening.
我们来跟踪几个案例 看看怎么样
Assume that Math.random generated a number that's equal to 0.433.
假设 Math.random 生成了一个等于 0.433 的随机数
The first thing we do is we multiply it by 10, making it 4.23,
首先我们需要让它乘以 10 使其变为 4.23
and then we cast it into an integer,
然后将其转换为整数
throwing away the fractional part so that becomes just four.
舍弃分数部分 所以该值变为 4
So our luckyIndex is four.
所以我们的 luckyIndex 是 4
So the last line just prints out news outlet of four.
最后一行代码会输出 newsOutlet [4] 的结果
And what is news out of four?
那 newsOutlet [4] 是什么呢？
It's zero, one, two,
这是 0、1、2、
three, four, it's this string here, which is AP.
3、4 就是这个字符串了 也就是 AP
If our random number that was generated was 0.987,
如果我们生成的随机数是 0.987
so that's in lucky,
这在 lucky 的范围里
we'll multiply that by 10, giving us 9.87.
所以将其乘以 10 也就得到了 9.87
And then we cast that into an integer so we throw away
将其转换为整数
that fractional part giving us nine,
舍弃其小数部分 于是我们得到了 9
and then we print out news outlet of nine,
由此我们输出 newsOutlet [9] 的结果
which happens to be Aljazeera.
也就是 Aljazeera
The same happens for any value that is generated for a variable lucky because
其它生成为变量 lucky 的值也一样
we always multiply it by 10 and then cast it into an integer. So there we go.
我们总会让该值乘以 10 然后将其转换为整数 这就大功告成啦